A Guide to the Ethel C. Clarke Papers, 1942-1970
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Ethel C. Clarke Papers, 1942-1970
The Library of Virginia
27769
6.3 cubic feet
Clarke, Ethel C. (1896-1971)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers were given by Mrs. Mary Clarke Reams, Richmond, on 31 December 1971; via Mr. Hunter Martin, attorney for Ethel C. Clarke's estate, Richmond. Some photostats of records in the State Archives, purchased by Mrs. Clarke, were discarded. One map of properties in the western part of Clover Hill District, Chesterfield County, was transferred to the Map Department.
Biographical Information
Ethel C. Clarke (1896-1971) was a professional genealogist who resided in Richmond, Virginia. She founded the Chesterfield County Historical Society.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1942-1970, of Ethel C. Clarke (1896-1971) of Richmond, Virginia, consisting of genealogical research on several Virginia families; papers relating to the Chesterfield County Historical Society and the Daughters of the American Revolution; and items from printed sources including History of Flowerdieu Hundred; Margaret Lynn Lewis diary; Powhatan County, Virginia, tax list; and the Richmond City Directory. Papers also include her personal papers, including biographical, financial, medical, and legal papers, as well as correspondence with a real estate agent.
Contents List
- General Correspondence.
  - 1946-1970., 5 folders. (Box 1)
- Genealogical Notes.
  - Alfriend family, 1676-1910. (Box 1)
  - Anderson family, 1752-1946 (also Lewis). (Box 1)
  - Archer family, 1843-1956. (Box 1)
  - Armistead family, 1635-1844 (also Bates, Burwell, Gregory, Higginson). (Box 1)
  - Ayres family, 1736-1920 (also Floyd, Hancock, Johnson, Nottingham). (Box 1)
  - Bailey-Bayley family, 1710-1811. (Box 2)
  - Baker family, 1774-1835. (Box 2)
  - Ball family, 1677-1909 (also Jesse). (Box 2)
  - Bass family, 1685-1894(also Moseley). (Box 2)
  - Bass family, 1685-1874., 4 folders. (Box 3)
  - Baugh family, 1668-1856. (Box 3)
  - Belcher family, 1720-1883. (Box 3)
  - Bell family, 1738-1860. (Box 3)
  - Bellamy family, 1647-1958. (Box 3)
  - Bolling family, 1690-1881 (also Pryor)., 2 folders. (Box 3)
  - Bolling family, 1721-1928. (Box 3)
  - Branch family, 1694-1814 (also Bass, Beasley). (Box 3)
  - Brooke family, 1749-1835. (Box 3)
  - Brooking family, 1670-1934 (also Vivion Clark)., 3 folders. (Box 3)
  - Bruce family, 1765-1871. (Box 3)
  - Bugg family, 1752-1791. (Box 3)
  - Burgess family, 1760-1962 (also Knight). (Box 4)
  - Burton family, 1632-1865. (Box 4)
  - Burwell family, 1625-1890 (also FitzPatrick). (Box 4)
  - Cameron family, 1755-1856 (also McEachen). (Box 4)
  - Carter family, 1750-1939. (Box 4)
  - Chappell family, 1635-1921 (also McKnight). (Box 4)
  - Cheatham family, 1630-1929 (also Clarke, Dorset, Gates, Goode, Hancock, Matheny)., 4 folders. (Box 4)
  - Clark-Clarke family, 1698-1963 (also Belcher, Jackson, Jones, Perkinson)., 2 folders. (Box 4)
  - Cobb family, 1870-1902. (Box 4)
  - Cogbill family, 1707-1940 (also Scott, Trueheart). (Box 5)
  - Cogbill family, 1672-1880 (also Oliver, Smith)., 5 folders. (Box 5)
  - Coleman family, 1760-1797. (Box 5)
  - Courtney family, 1782-1806 (also Catchem). (Box 5)
  - Cox family, 1786-1846. (Box 5)
  - Crews family, 1730-1950 (also Rainwater, Taylor). (Box 5)
  - Crowley family, 1682-1826. (Box 5)
  - Crump family, 1667-1911. (Box 5)
  - Crutcher family, 1778-1850 (also Adams, Clay). (Box 5)
  - Curry family, 1708-1850 (also Bland). (Box 5)
  - Davis family, 1781-1880 (also Douglas). (Box 6)
  - Dennis family, 1691-1883 (also Bessom). (Box 6)
  - Dorset family, 1681-1912 (also Bailey, Bailie., 3 folders. (Box 6)
  - Dunnavant family, 1701-1853. (Box 6)
  - Edwards family, 1781-1830 (also Powell). (Box 3)
  - Elam family, 1636-1792. (Box 6)
  - Eppes family, 1597-1803. (Box 6)
  - Fergusson family, 1697-1875., 2 folders. (Box 6)
  - Fitzhugh family, 1614-1850 (also Rose). (Box 6)
  - Flournoy family, 1663-1935 (also Dooley, Harris)., 4 folders. (Box 6)
  - Foster family, 1752-1900 (also Adams). (Box 7)
  - Garland family, 1628-1770 (also Waters). (Box 7)
  - Garthright family, 1750-1857. (Box 7)
  - Gates family, 1651-1840. (Box 7)
  - Goode family, 1711-1840. (Box 7)
  - Goodman family, 1623-1950. (Box 7)
  - Gower family, 1676-1860 (also Robertson). (Box 7)
  - Grant family, 1753-1875. (Box 7)
  - Gregory family, 1700-1930 (also Gates, Hudson)., 5 folders. (Box 7)
  - Haddock family, 1642-1930. (Box 7)
  - Hancock family, 1608-1837 (also Cheek, Hudson, Watkins). (Box 8)
  - Harris family, 1658-1850. (Box 8)
  - Harris family, 1671-1934., 3 folders. (Box 8)
  - Harrison family, 1649-1959 (also Malone). (Box 8)
  - Harrison family, 1645-1894., 3 folders. (Box 9)
  - Haskins family, 1661-1883. (Box 9)
  - Hatcher family, 1694-1881. (Box 9)
  - Hinton family, 1723-1880. (Box 9)
  - Hite family, 1689-1900., 3 folders. (Box 9)
  - Holland family, 1704-1795. (Box 9)
  - Holt family, 1650-1858. (Box 9)
  - Hudson family, 1667-1799. (Box 9)
  - Humphrey family, 1763-1826. (Box 9)
  - Inge family, 1770-1859. (Box 9)
  - Irby family, 1612-1866. (Box 9)
  - Jackson family, 1720-1866 (also Fuqua, Nesbitt, Ward)., 2 folders. (Box 9)
  - James family, 1701-1754 (also Grayson). (Box 10)
  - Jefferies family, 1679-1906 (also Wells). (Box 10)
  - Jesse family, 1717-1882 (also Ball). (Box 10)
  - Johnson family, 1726-1902 (also Nelson, Peachey, Walker). (Box 10)
  - Johnston family, 1763-1908. (Box 10)
  - Keith family, 1760-1943 (also Exum). (Box 10)
  - Lane family, 1751-1835 (also Bugg). (Box 10)
  - Laprade family, 1724-1959. (Box 10)
  - Lawrence family, 1793-1851 (also Polley). (Box 10)
  - Lee family, 1657-1932. (Box 10)
  - Lindsay family, 1770-1844. (Box 10)
  - Lipscomb family, 1776-1889 (also Montague). (Box 10)
  - Lockett family, 1692-1862. (Box 10)
  - Loving family, 1761-1864 (also Poynter). (Box 10)
  - McGehee family, 1701-1869. (Box 10)
  - Maddox family, 1726-1833 (also Allen, Trabue). (Box 10)
  - Mangum family, 1736-1958 (also McLemore, Parker)., 5 folders. (Box 10)
  - Marsh family, 1781-1860. (Box 10)
  - Marshall family, 1650-1907. (Box 10)
  - Massey family, 1682-1904 (also Lanier, Rives). (Box 10)
  - Mayo family, 1737-1933. (Box 10)
  - Moody family, 1755-1802. (Box 10)
  - Moore family, 1721-1932 (also Hobson, Langhorne). (Box 11)
  - Morris family, 1718-1908. (Box 11)
  - Mosby family, 1792-1850. (Box 11)
  - Moseley family, 1692-1868 (also Clark, Ligon). (Box 11)
  - Neal family, 1636-1953 (also Wills). (Box 11)
  - Nelson family, 1749-1925 (also Harris)., 2 folders. (Box 11)
  - Noble family, 1727-1864. (Box 11)
  - Pankey family, 1779-1897 (also Gregory). (Box 11)
  - Parker family, 1656-1913., 2 folders. (Box 11)
  - Patrick family, 1638-1834 (also Boisseau, FitzPatrick). (Box 11)
  - Perkinson family, 1697-1880. (Box 11)
  - Pitchford family, 1762-1898 (also Loyd). (Box 11)
  - Preston family, 1779-1849. (Box 11)
  - Pride family, 1695-1742. (Box 11)
  - Puckett family, 1675-1851. (Box 11)
  - Quarles family, 1670-1869 (also Gillett). (Box 11)
  - Quisenberry family, 1781-1893 (also Shearer). (Box 11)
  - Roberts family, 1732-1844 (also Martin). (Box 11)
  - Robertson family, 1732-1920(also Jones, Lowry)., 2 folders. (Box 11)
  - Rose family, 1709-1840. (Box 12)
  - Samford family, 1795-1858 (also Bishop). (Box 12)
  - Scott family, 1707-1915. (Box 12)
  - Shield family, 1717-1840 (also DeLong). (Box 12)
  - Smith family, 1786-1852 (also Dodson). (Box 12)
  - Talbott family, 1718-1866 (also Gregory, Woodcock). (Box 12)
  - Taylor family, 1769-1872 (also Gregory, Woodcock). (Box 12)
  - Terry family, 1732-1938 (also Puckett). (Box 12)
  - Thompson family, 1782-1850. (Box 12)
  - Thurmond family, 1734-1840 (also Goode). (Box 12)
  - Timberlake family, 1752-1895. (Box 12)
  - Traylor family, 1694-1902. (Box 12)
  - Trueheart family, 1707-1940 (also Mosby, Rose, Scott). (Box 12)
  - Turpin family, 1736-1945 (also Clark, Duval). (Box 12)
  - Vineyard family, 1754-1957. (Box 12)
  - Virdin family, 1800-1914. (Box 12)
  - Walker family, 1740-1850 (also Gathright, Harrison). (Box 12)
  - Walthall family, 1716-1906. (Box 12)
  - Ward family, 1724-1886., 2 folders. (Box 12)
  - Watkins family, 1755-1894. (Box 12)
  - Wells family, 1679-1961. (Box 12)
  - Williams family, 1662-1839. (Box 12)
  - Wilson family, 1659-1928. (Box 12)
  - Wooldridge family, 1753-1884. (Box 12)
  - Worsham family, 1718-1812. (Box 12)
  - Yancey family, 1765-1850 (also Goode, Harrison). (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous (includes Batte, Beazley, Brackett, Carr, Cullum, Davis, Glover, Hobb, Hogg, Jones, Lowe, Morgan, Morris, O'Brien, Parham, Rudd, Sims, Tatum, Terry, Turner, Updegraff). (Box 13)
  - General census and tax lists information, 1800-1850. (Box 13)
- Historical and Patriotic Organizations.
  - Chesterfield County Historical Society, 1963-1965. (Box 13)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1964-1965. (Box 13)
- Printed Matter.
  - Historical and geographical publications, 1954, 1967-1968, and undated. (Box 13)
  - History of Flowerdieu Hundred, 1607-1948. (Box 13)
  - Margaret Lynn Lewis' diary, typed copy, undated. (Box 13)
  - Powhatan County tax list, 1962. (Box 13)
  - Richmond City Directory, 1873-1874. (Box 13)
- Personal Papers.
  - Biographical, 1932, 1934. (Box 14)
  - Mrs. Ola Clarke, 1949-1951, 1956, 1960. (Box 14)
  - Financial, 1965-1967. (Box 14)
  - Hicks estate, 1964-1966. (Box 14)
  - Legal papers, 1945, 1950-1952, 1966-1967. (Box 14)
  - Medical care, 1969. (Box 14)
  - Property in Chesterfield County, 1881 and Richmond, 1962-1964. (Box 14)
  - Social Security, 1966-1968. (Box 14)
- G. B. Lorraine, Real Estate Agent.
  - Correspondence, 1942-1945, 1956, 1968-1970., 7 folders. (Box 14)